Born 1993, Baku Azerbaijan

Address Warsaw, Poland 00-732

Contact +48 662 124 745 nijatsafarli@gmail.com

Portfolio on my website nijatsafarli.com







Graphic Designer

With over 7 years of experience as a graphic designer and design manager, I've been on a journey to find the best design solutions for a variety of industries including oil, construction, electronics, banking, software and more. I firmly believe that good design is a critical element for businesses to develop and expand. It's a great joy for me to utilize my skills and experience to impact this process.

It all started with pencil drawings. First, it was just a hobby, but it eventually became a professional pleasure. As an illustrator, I incorporate my drawing skills into nearly every project, creating a unique style for each design solution. Besides using illustrations in most projects, I also developed myself as an individual artist and started creating numerous illustrations for pure enjoyment. Even though it's still a professional hobby, it's also a desired skill for many

WORK EXPERIENCE

PLANHAT LLC

[Customer Success Software Platform]

Sweden / Full-time remote work

• Creating all design creatives of company

Digital Designer

- Creating visual concepts of documents, e-books and catalogues
- Re-shaping design structure of company
- Creating web illustrations for website and application
- Designing webinar and podcast visuals

AZERBAIJAN NATIONAL ANTI-DOPING AGENCY (AMADA)

[Govermental sport inspection organisation]

June 2020 - December 2021

Design Manager

- Manage and create all design creatives of company
- Creating visual concepts of events and conferences Leading photographes&videographes shooting and
- finalizing products with them • Creating educational anti-doping materials, such as, flyers,
- presentations, handbooks, social media posters and etc. Participating in departmental strategic planning
- Creating annual report catalogue by unique concepts

ATL CONSULTING LLC

[360° marketing service- Advertisement company]

May 2019 - June 2020

Graphic Designer

- Presenting the briefs and concepts based on the client's needs and vision
- Working with copywriter and creative director to produce final design
- Creating visual concepts in line with the customer's needs · Providing graphic images, illustrations, motion videos,
- retouched images, web designs, print materials, mockups and sketches • Participating in departmental strategic planning

[Chain of the biggest electronics household product stores

BAKU ELECTRONICS LLC

May 2018 - March 2019

Graphic Designer Creating social media image and video visuals

- Designing print materials, e-books, catalogues, billboards,
- promo materials, flyer and posters based on campaigns or creative directions Creating key visuals for sale campaigns and adapting
 - it to various layouts and also to HTML5 banners

TECHNOL LLC [First motor oil company in Caucasus]

May 2017 - May 2018

Graphic Designer

- Conceptualizing visuals based on creative directions
- Thinking creatively to produce new ideas and concepts and developing interactive design Creating daily social media images, GIFs and videos

• Design product labels and preparing them ready for print

FREELANCE WORK EXPERIENCE

Feburary 2016 - Present Freelance works have always been an opportunity to enter a different business fields. Besides permanent job freelancing is

a great way of enlarging portfolio with different kind of projecst and companies.



Technol



HAYSTACK









EDUCATION

Business Administration & Management

BSc Business Administration

Erasmus Exchange Programme January 2014 - July 2014

Tartu University Estonia, Tartu

Akdeniz University Turkey, Antalya

DESIGN SKILLS

Graphic Design Pencil drawing

Azerbaijan / Native

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Adobe InDesign Adobe After Effects Corel Draw Suit Adobe XD Figma Blender Google Web Designer Audacity

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

SOFTWARE KNOWLEDGE

Art Direction Background Design Character Design Branding 3D knowledge **Motion Graphics**

Web Design Video Editing

Turkish / Native English / Advanced Russian / Elementary Polish/ Elementary

OTHER SKILLS

Fully/Part-time working

Communication skills

Creative thinking

Full Management ability

Innovative approach

Analytic solving

Extensive experience with computer software&hardware

Availibility to travel

SOCIAL MEDIA PROFILES

/ Digital Pen

/ Nijat Safarli

/nijatsafarli

Nijat Safarli

www.nijatsafarli.com

Last updated in August 2023